Dylan Armstrong

Orlando, FL | (407) 230-1632 | <u>Dylan.Craig.Armstrong@gmail.com</u>

Linked In: https://www.linkedin.com/in/Dylan-Armstrong

Github: https://github.com/DoleTM | Portfolio: https://doletm.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Web Developer specializing in creative front-end web pages and fluid back-end functionality. Experience in inventory management implementing Agile practices such as using an online Kanban board, testing in batches and iterating reusability. Ability to create platforms practical for the end user through hands on experience and connecting data. Strong communication skills with a demonstrated history of leading without authority.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.js | MySQL/Postgres | Javascript | JSON | API | JQuery | MongoDB | React | CSS/SASS | HTML | FTP | PHP | Angular | Version Control/Git | MVC | Bootstrap | OOP | Ember.js | Heroku | Materialize | Command Line

PROJECTS

Safely: A website that uses geolocation or zip code that determines if they are safe based on a crime data API.

- Responsible for connecting and displaying the data from Firebase to the front end webpage.
- □ Voted first place in functionality, creativity and presentation out of 12 different projects.
- This project uses Tailwind, Javascript/JQuery, Orlando City Crime API, Firebase and CanvasJS.

Deployed site: https://soc33.github.io/Safely/ | GitHub Repo: https://github.com/soc33/Safely/

Furiends: Social media platform designed for the user to post pictures of their pets.

- Responsible for back end functionality and contributing to the front end User Interface.
- After making an account the user is able to upload and comment on photos.
- This project uses Bootstrap, EJS, Cloudinary, Passport.js, Bcrypt.js, DataURI, MySQL/Sequelize, MVC.

Deployed site: https://agile-gorge-44903.herokuapp.com/ | GitHub Repo: https://github.com/gutierrez88/Furiends

Web-Scrape: Webpage that scrapes articles from the web and saves favorites/comments in a database.

- □ Sole contributor from concept to production.
- ☐ Utilizes the CRUD functions for comments on blog posts.
- ☐ This project uses Materialize, Custom CSS, Javascript/JQuery, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, Cheerio.

Deployed site: https://infinite-bastion-71270.herokuapp.com/ | GitHub Repo:https://github.cpm/DoleTM/Web-Scrape

EXPERIENCE

AdventHealth, Orlando, FL — *Inventory Control PAR Technician* | Jan 2019 - Present

- Responsible for configuring and maintaining the physical hardware in 200+ automated supply rooms across 8 hospitals in the Orlando area.
- ☐ Analyze trends through client side programs to correct issues by using my database knowledge to prevent problems from occurring in real time.
- Implemented a Kanban board to maintain the flow of project completion and daily activities.
- Provide technical training to the support staff that utilizes the automated hardware daily.

Injector Support & Service, Winter Garden, FL — Shipping Manager | Feb 2017 - Dec 2018

- Organized a new 10,000 sqft. warehouse facility, containing 3000+ parts and equipment that maximized efficiency for all departments.
- Recognized by CEO for compiling 8 years of scattered data into one streamlined log within a month.
- Created a comprehensive procedure handbook that establishes guidelines, sets the daily goals and sustains my organizational knowledge.
- ☐ Improved the return rate of core exchanges by 50% within a year by maintaining a client relationship through weekly phone calls and emails.

Victory Tailgate, Orlando, FL — *Production Control Supervisor* | Nov 2014 - Jan 2017

- ☐ Trained employees on necessary inventory and production control workflows & processes.
- ☐ Made operational decisions, troubleshoot problems and took corrective actions to lead with continuous improvement.
- Utilized supply and sales forecasting data to establish an effective production plan.
- Changed production plan as needed to alleviate shortages and meet demand requirements.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate (Coding Bootcamp): University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL A 24-week intensive program focused on technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, PHP, AJAX, JSON, Express, Handlebars.js & ReactJS.